# JESSICA CESARIO

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

# CONTACT



954-593-6768



jessica.cesario@gmail.com



Orlando, FL 32810

# SKILLS

## **PROFESSIONAL**

- Attention to Detail
- Communication
- Perceptivity
- Critical Thinking
- Deadline Management
- Organizational Skills
- Prioritizing
- Problem-solving
- **Analytical Skills**

#### **CREATIVE**

- Aesthetics
- Balancing Artistry with Audience **Appeal**
- Visually Representing Ideas
- Visually Solving Problems
- Brainstorming
- Branding
- Text and Layout
- Photo Manipulation

## EDUCATION

DIGITAL MEDIA | GRAPHIC DESIGN UCF | Orlando, FL 2014 - 2017

**GENERAL EDUCATION** Valencia College | Orlando, FL 2010 - 2012

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

### USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Throughout my career, I have worked to establish and apply a set of design and documentation standards, strategies, and principles used in harmony with design and branding interactions toward the best final product. I use layout, visual representations, physical objects, space, motion, and interaction behavior to determine how to use assets and data to achieve objectives in an emotionally resonant manner. I look to utilize psychological principles, ergonomics, and cognitive science to design holistic experiences around abilities, motivations, and the needs of the user.

# EXPERIENCE

### LIVE USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Electronic Arts | Orlando, FL | 2017 - Present

As the art lead for MUT live content, I focused on owning and driving all key areas within the mode and some key areas outside of the game.

- Handled branding and asset creation for all MUT programs, with a focus on creating best practices, since Madden 17
- Was a critical part of the hiring process, and assisted with onboarding, managing and providing feedback for new team members
- Built and maintained collaborative relationships with designers, producers, partners, stakeholders, and cross disciplinary teams
- KEY ACHIEVEMENTS: 2021 Spot Stock Award for my work as acting live art manager; 2019 and 2017 live service Sharkie Award for outstanding achievement

## **GRAPHIC DESIGN INTERN**

Electronic Arts | Orlando, FL | 2017

I focused on supporting the senior artists succeed in their roles.

Handled program branding and asset creation for all assets within Madden **Ultimate Team** 

#### FREELANCE SERVICE AND MARKETING DESIGNER

The Smiling Bison | Orlando, FL | 2016 – 2017 Little Venice | Hollywood, FL | 2010 – 2015

I took small, unorganized brands and transformed them into a more cohesive whole with polished assets in a variety of digital and print formats.

- Created all assets for and ran all social media presences, aimed at marketing for the company and brand
- Coordinated with talent to book venue events and translated that into branded, easily digestible event schedules